MURALIDHARAN BUANDASAN NO.24, JALAN FLORA 1/7, TAMAN PULAI FLORA, 81300 SKUDAI, JOHOR

TEL: +60197701011(H/P)

E-MAIL: m.buandasan@gmail.com



A) CAREER OBJECTIVE

To obtain a position in a technology-oriented company who can offer career advancement & development of my personal skills and ability. In return, to contribute my extensive knowledge in the Quality Engineering field, maximise my technical skills & implement Quality Assurance best practices for the continuous improvement of the company especially in the aspect of Quality Management.

B) HIGHLIGHTS

More than 8 years of experience in the Quality Assurance field with 3 years as Senior Quality Engineer attached to a Contract Manufacturer manufacturing Printed Circuit Board Assembly for a MNC customer - Agilent Technologies Inc.

Currently attached to an UK based MNC – **Smiths Detection** a designer and manufacturer of sensors that detect and identify explosives, weapons, chemical agents, biohazards, nuclear & radioactive material, narcotics and contraband.

Key competencies:

Vast experience in Continuous Quality Improvement using various quality management tools namely PDCA, FMEA, Cause & Effect Diagram, 8D reporting, Control Charts and familiar with DOE & Six Sigma methodology

Key achievements:

- Involved in various continuous quality improvement projects which **contributed** cost savings up to USD 180k per year
- Continuous achievement in maintaining the Outgoing Inspection Yield at more than 90% and customer monitoring DPPM at below 50
- Contributed in the qualification of less critical items (sourced from local suppliers instead of from Germany) for generator materials which slashed down generator assembly cost by 25%
- Involved in the various internal and external audits and successfully being certified by certification bodies such as PSB: TUV (ISO 9001:2008 & ISO 14001:2004), UL, SIRIM (CSA) and also by customers on product and process audits
- Development of the Quality Management System of Smiths Detection Malaysia and successfully coordinated in achieving the ISO 9001:2008 certification by German DQS certification body for the newly set up company
- Created and **established the Quality Standards and Inspection Criteria** for the Generator and Detector Boards Assembly

Working in these environment has equipped me with excellent problem solving tools namely and communication skills which has led me to be an analytical, result orientated, team player, adaptable, self-motivated, fast learner and an aggressive individual in pursuing personal goals as well as company objectives.

D) EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND Year

Institute & Qualification

1996 – 2001 : Bachelor of Electrical Engineering (Power)
University Technology of Malaysia

E) WORKING EXPERIENCE

1) Sep 2012 - Till now QUALITY ENGINEER (SMITHS DETECTION SDN BHD - MANUFACTURING)

Job Description:

- a) **Focal Quality contact** for sub-assemblies ie. generators, detector boards and lead shielding manufacturing be it for internal, customers and also for our Centre of Excellence in Germany
- b) Responsible to **define and create the quality standards** and also the **quality inspection criteria** for all sub-assemblies as mentioned above
- c) Conduct **process audit** for sub-assembly lines to ensure in-built quality is maintained and constantly achieved
- d) Prepare **weekly and monthly report for Global Management** review and drive for improvement using collected data
- e) Qualify the production technicians before they are certified to be released for mass production build
- f) Assess and decide on the test results of the generator and detector board for those results which does not meet the test data specification
- g) Perform troubleshooting of a failed generator together with the Manufacturing Engineer
- h) As the **company document controller**, responsible to ensure that the QMS and EHS document are updated accordingly
- i) Responsible to **track the calibration master list** to ensure all test and measuring equipment are registered and within the calibration period

Achievement and Job Highlights:

- **Pioneer team** for Smiths Detection Malaysia
- Attended a **5 weeks training** in Smiths Heimann (Centre of Excellence), **Wiesbaden, Germany** for the generator assembly, test and also on the quality aspects
- Successfully completed the transfer project for generator assembly including the necessary approval from AELB and also the validation process within 3 months
- Since Smiths Detection Malaysia is a new setup, coordinated with the QMR in establishing the QMS system and successfully certified by German DQS as a ISO 9001:2008 certified company in June 2013
- Lead the kaizen team in carrying out various Kaizen projects which reduced the operating cost up to USD 10k per year, lessen the risk of safety hazards and increase the productivity by 25%

Trainings Attended:

- Understanding, Documenting & Implementing an ISO9001:2008 Quality Management System
- OHSAS 18001 & ISO 14001 Awareness
- Hazard Identification, Risk Assessment & Determining Controls (HIRADC)
- Radiation Safety
- Emergency Response Plan (ERP)
- Safe Chemical Handling

2) Dec 2008 - Sep 2012 SENIOR QUALITY ENGINEER - AGILENT PRODUCT (PINTARMAS SDN BHD - VENTURE GROUP)

Job Description:

- a) Assist the Quality Manager in managing 4 Quality Engineers, 2 Supervisors & 50 over inspectors and to manage internal and external quality matters by driving the team to ensure continuous quality improvement within the organization
- b) Organize, coordinate and conduct periodic process, system and compliance audits to ensure the facility is always ready for any audits
- c) Attend monthly F2F (Face to Face) meeting with customer to review the monthly performance
- d) Lead audits conducted by customers on the processes involved, external certification bodies for **ISO 9001:2008, UL & CSA certifications**. Followed by co-ordinating within the team to take necessary actions if there is any non-conformance or observations found during the audit. This would be followed by the corrective action report to respective customers.

Achievement and Job Highlights:

- **Promoted as a Senior Engineer** within 3 years of joining the company
- Involved and contributed in the various quality improvement projects by utilizing Quality Management Tools including DOE & Six Sigma methodology which yielded to **cost savings up to USD 180k per year**
- Continuous achievement of customer satisfaction by having **DPPM below 50** and maintaining being the **top preferred supplier**

Trainings Attended:

- Six Sigma Green Belt
- Certified IPC Specialist
- Problem Solving Through 7QC Tool
- Statistical Process Control (SPC)
- Understanding, Implementing and Auditing ISO 14001:2004
- Internal QMS Auditing by Process Approach
- Process FMEA

3) Jan 2006 - Nov 2008 QUALITY ENGINEER - AGILENT PRODUCT (PINTARMAS SDN BHD - VENTURE GROUP)

Job Description:

- a) Focal person for customer contact on any quality or technical issues that needs immediate attention.
- b) To co-ordinate quality or technical issues based on feedback from customers, within various internal departments such as the process, test, equipment, procurement & etc. and ensuring proper corrective action if necessary, is taken to prevent recurrence of the issue.
- c) To handle & manage products returned by customers due to quality issues and arrange for necessary rework to be done before returning them back to customers.
- d) Lead audits conducted by customers on the processes involved & ISO 9001 and followed by co-ordinating within the team to take necessary actions if there is any non-conformance or observations found during the audit. This would be followed by the corrective action report to respective customers.
- e) Compiling & preparing weekly/monthly report from various processes that would be shared with internal team and also with customers.
- f) To monitor Outgoing QA performance and conduct internal audits and improvement together with team members to increase the standard of quality of the product.

4) January 2004 - December 2005
SENIOR PROJECT EXECUTIVE - UTILITY DEPARTMENT
February 2002 - December 2003
PROJECT EXECUTIVE - UTILITY DEPARTMENT
(TALAM CORPORATION BERHAD)

Job Description:

- a) **Project Management** Coordinating and monitoring Project Executives of the respective projects besides liaison with *TNB*, *SYABAS* and *MPSJ*. Preparing work schedules for the Project Executives to ensure project is completed within targeted time.
- b) Preparing weekly and monthly report to be submitted to Head of Department, which would then be tabled during Management Meetings.
- c) Attend weekly Management Meetings to brief management on progress, to plan for the coming week and also to highlight problems faced with the Authority if there are any.
- d) Attend monthly meeting with *Tenaga Nasional Berhad* Engineers to discuss the progress of their planning and implementation stage in providing supply to the projects.

F) COMPUTER KNOWLEDGE

- Proficient in Microsoft Office and Basic Knowledge in Microsoft Project.
- Basic knowledge in SAP

G) ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Current Salary : RM 5,096

Expected Salary : RM 7,000 (Neg.)

H) REFEREE

i) Mdm. Noridah Ahmad Quality Manager, Pintarmas Sdn Bhd (Venture)

H/P: 0177382339

ii) Mr. Muniandy Shunmugam General Manager, Antranet Sdn Bhd

H/P:012-3053780